<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sigcomm | Mininet]]></title>
  <link href="http://mininet.org/blog/categories/sigcomm/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mininet.org/"/>
  <updated>2021-03-12T09:27:33-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mininet.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mininet Project Contributors]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mininet wins ACM SIGCOMM Test of Time Paper Award]]></title>
    <link href="http://mininet.org/blog/2020/06/29/mininet-paper-wins-sigcomm-test-of-time-award/"/>
    <updated>2020-06-29T17:23:04-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mininet.org/blog/2020/06/29/mininet-paper-wins-sigcomm-test-of-time-award</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that our original HotNets paper,
<a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/hotnets/2010/papers/a19-lantz.pdf">A Network in a Laptop: Rapid Prototyping for Software-Defined Networks</a>, has won the
<a href="http://www.sigcomm.org/awards/test-of-time-paper-award">ACM SIGCOMM Test of Time Paper Award</a>.</p>

<p>Congratulations to the authors, Bob Lantz, Brandon Heller, and Nick
McKeown, and congratulations and thanks to the many researchers,
teachers, students, users, collaborators, and project contributors who
have used and continue to use Mininet to help usher in the SDN
revolution and improve the practice of computer networking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Congrats to Mininet SIGCOMM Hackathon winners!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mininet.org/blog/2018/08/27/sigcomm2018-hackathon-winners/"/>
    <updated>2018-08-27T15:39:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mininet.org/blog/2018/08/27/sigcomm2018-hackathon-winners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations to Alexander Jung, Michał Król and Torsten Runge, who
prototyped a Mininet node class for launching unikernels - small
application-specific kernel images, basically an application linked
with a library OS, ClickOS being one example - and ended up placing in
the SIGCOMM 2018 Hackathon!</p>

<p><a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2018/hackathon.html">http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2018/hackathon.html</a></p>

<p>In their case they used Rumprun as the unikernel system and qemu/kvm
to launch it:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://github.com/nderjung/mininet">http://github.com/nderjung/mininet</a> (Branch: <code>devel/rump</code>)</li>
  <li><a href="http://github.com/rumpkernel/rumprun/">http://github.com/rumpkernel/rumprun/</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://unikernel.org">http://unikernel.org</a></li>
</ul>

<p>They are planning on continuing to work on it, so I hope we can get something
simple and useful running and perhaps added to Mininet!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mininet wins ACM SIGCOMM SOSR Software Systems Award !]]></title>
    <link href="http://mininet.org/blog/2017/04/05/mininet-wins-sosr-systems-award/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-05T11:04:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mininet.org/blog/2017/04/05/mininet-wins-sosr-systems-award</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that <strong>Mininet has won the
<a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sosr/2017/award.html">ACM SIGCOMM SOSR Software Systems Award</a>!</strong></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The ACM SIGCOMM SOSR Software Systems Award is given to an individual
or an institution to recognize the development of a software system
that has had a significant impact on SDN research, implementations,
and tools. The impact may be reflected in the widespread adoption of
the system, or of its underlying concepts, by the wider SDN community,
either in research projects, in the open-source community, or
commercially.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The award also includes an invited talk, and the talk slides may be found
<a href="https://github.com/mininet/mininet/wiki/Publications#presentations-and-slides">here</a>.</p>

<p>The SOSR 2017 program and proceedings may be found <a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sosr/2017/program.html">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Mininet’s ongoing success and impact would not be possible without the
support and contributions from the Mininet community, so we’d like to
take this opportunity to thank everyone and to say that we look
forward to working together to continue to make Mininet a better and
more useful system!</strong></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minininet Tutorial at SIGCOMM]]></title>
    <link href="http://mininet.org/blog/2014/12/08/mininet-tutorial-at-sigcomm/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T12:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mininet.org/blog/2014/12/08/mininet-tutorial-at-sigcomm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Materials from our tutorial at SIGCOMM 2014,
<a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2014/tutorial-mininet.php">“Teaching Computer Networking with Mininet”</a>, are available on
<a href="http://teaching.mininet.org">teaching.mininet.org</a>.
The original announcement follows.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Call for Participation:</strong></p>

<h3 id="mininet-tutorial---teaching-computer-networking-with-mininet">Mininet Tutorial - Teaching Computer Networking with Mininet</h3>

<p><a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2014/tutorial-mininet.php">http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2014/tutorial-mininet.php</a></p>

<p><strong>August 18th, Chicago, USA (in conjunction with SIGCOMM)</strong></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="important-dates">Important Dates</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Early Registration Deadline: July 11th, 11:59pm CDT</li>
  <li>Late Registration: July 12th - August 18th</li>
  <li>Tutorial Date: August 18th 8:30am - 12:00pm</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="objective">Objective</h3>

<p>Sharing our experiences using the Mininet network
emulation platform to teach computer networking in a variety of
contexts ranging from small on-campus courses (Stanford, Georgia Tech,
MIT) to massive online courses. We believe that the Mininet platform
can make teaching and learning computer networking more fun and
effective by facilitating experiential learning.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="program">Program</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Introduce <a href="http://mininet.org">Mininet</a> to the broader network community, including its capabilities and limitations and some example use cases.</li>
  <li>Familiarize attendees with Mininet through hands-on exercises.</li>
  <li>Share our experiences using Mininet since 2011 for on-campus and massive online courses at Stanford, Georgia Tech and MIT.</li>
  <li>Disseminate assignments that we used at our universities and help to develop and expand an online repository of Mininet courseware.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="speakers-and-panelists">Speakers and Panelists</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Bob Lantz - ON.Lab</li>
  <li>Te-Yuan (TY) Huang - Stanford</li>
  <li>Vimalkumar Jeyakumar - Stanford</li>
  <li>Brian O’Connor - ON.Lab</li>
  <li>Nick Feamster - Georgia Tech</li>
  <li>Keith Winstein - MIT</li>
  <li>Anirudh Sivaraman - MIT</li>
</ul>

<hr />
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
